WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
I think it's held up very well,
all things considered.
Especially after all that rain.
How's the house team coming on?
Because we're taking this
very seriously in the village.
Nobody takes it more seriously
than his lordship, Dad,
whatever he likes to pretend.
Mr Bates has had his rest now
and wants to get back to work.
It's time to draw a line under
this whole unfortunate episode.
So I go out the window.
I cannot hide that I find
your situation revolting.
But, whether or not you believe me,
I am not entirely unsympathetic.
You have been twisted by nature
into something foul,
and even I can see
that you did not ask for it.
I think it better
that you resign, quietly,
citing the excuse
that Mr Bates has returned.
I will write
a perfectly acceptable reference
and you'll find that there's nothing
about it that's hard to explain.
I see.
What about tonight?
It's nearly time to change,
so you should dress him tonight
and let Mr Bates take over tomorrow.
I'm not foul, Mr Carson.
I'm not the same as you,
but I'm not foul.
Yes, well...
We've spoken enough on this subject.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'll ring the gong.
Come along, Miss O'Brien.
Stop eavesdropping and do some work.
I don't know what you...
How are you getting on
with the cricket team?
We should be all right.
We've still got Thomas, thank God.
Won't he be leaving soon?
Not before the match,
if I've got anything to do with it.
One of the gardeners told Anna
their team is in terrific shape.
It's so unfair the outside staff
play for the village.
Why don't you support the house
AND the village? You own both.
But I'm captain of the house team.
If I were you I'd be captain
of the village. They always win.
Not always.
Usually, but not always.
Mary, you look
as if you're in a trance.
What were you doing in London?
It's worn you out.
Maybe. I'll try and rest tomorrow.
Crikey.
I'd better go.
Before you do,
a little bird tells me
Mr Carson has made up his mind
to deal with Thomas after all.
It's about time.
If you want to register your anger
at how Thomas treated you,
now is the hour.
I'm not sure. I'm still disgusted
by the whole thing, obviously.
Obviously.
But if you don't speak out,
people might think
you weren't disgusted at all.
Now you must excuse me.
I ought to be upstairs.
Anna! What are you doing out here?
Her ladyship's with Lady Mary, sir.
I'm afraid she's going to be late.
Let me see what's happening.
You couldn't be in better hands
than Dr Ryder's, truly.
I hope to God you're right.
Anna's worried you're getting late.
Heavens, you made me jump.
I must go. O'Brien will scold me.
Anna?
What were you talking about?
Nothing.
Women's stuff.
Your ears must have been burning
earlier. Papa was discussing
the cricket match.
The village thrashed us last year.
I suppose I'll have to play.
You suppose right.
Because of last year he's absolutely
determined to win this time.
Bates must count himself lucky
to be out of it.
I think he'd like
to walk normally, sir,
even if playing cricket
was the price he had to pay.
Of course he would. I'm so sorry.
That was stupid of me.
It's quite all right, sir.
I was only joking.
Oh, there's no question
that some people have a feel for it.
I think cricket's
like anything else.
When you learn it as a child,
there's an understanding
that is hard to come by later.
And with a father like mine...
I was brought up
with cricket in my blood.
Why have you never played in a match
before? How could I? I didn't work
at the house until this year.
I could hardly play
for the village team.
We'll have to start
a fan club, won't we?
That's kind, Ivy, but I just
want to do my best for the house.
That's all the reward I seek.
Your modesty is an example
to us all, Mr Molesley.
What is that you're so glued to?
This week's column.
I've got to send it off tomorrow.
What's it about?
The poor soldiers. How many are
reduced to begging on the streets.
And some officers are working
as dance partners in nightclubs.
After the trenches, even the Embassy
Club must seem an improvement.
You shouldn't make fun of them.
She's forgetting that you were
in the trenches and she wasn't.
She must be 18 by now.
Little Rose, 18? Yes. How scary!
Hello.
It's quite a responsibility.
Well, I couldn't say no.
Her mother is my niece
and my godchild, and she
asked it as a special favour.
Apparently, she hates London.
And they can't get to Scotland
until July.
Poor Shrimpie. His work
keeps him nailed to his desk.
She hates London, so she's coming
to a great-aunt in Yorkshire
to have a good time? Mm-hm.
How original.
Don't be silly. Of course you will.
No, I won't.
I'd like to help but I've never
played a game of cricket in my life.
Oddly, the game was never
a part of my childhood.
Didn't you play last year?
No, nor the year before that.
The fact is I've never played
cricket. But couldn't you try?
Robert! Stop being such a bully.
Let's just have a nice dinner.
I'm afraid I've heard
Mr Carson's going to let him off.
What can I do about it?
Say you won't tolerate it.
Unless he's going to give him a bad
reference, you'll tell the police.
I couldn't do that. Could I?
Why not?
And won't you have to,
if you don't want folk to think
there's something funny about you?
It's a good job
that's supposed to be eaten cold.
Are you sure about Rose? Wouldn't
it be better if she stayed here?
No, no, no.
I'm quite looking forward to it.
I couldn't manage an 18-year-old
these days. I wouldn't know
what she was talking about.
My husband was a great traveller,
so I've spent many happy evenings
without understanding a word.
The thing is to keep smiling
and never look as if you disapprove.
So, Bates, I'll see you
on duty tomorrow.
Good night, Barrow. You do know
I wish you every good fortune?
I believe so. Thank you, m'lord.
To the victor the spoils.
What will you do?
Oh, what's it to you?
You're right. It's nothing to me.
If we can buy out Simpson
and Tucker, quite a chunk
of the estate will be back in hand.
We'll be operating a real business.
That's why I think the cricket
may have come at rather a good time.
Why? Because you think if you get
a few runs and catch someone out,
Papa will accept all this gladly?
I think the cricket will show him
it doesn't mean we can't keep up
the old traditions as well.
And I'm to help persuade him?
Of course. You're on MY team now.
You can kiss me, but that's it.
Why? Haven't you missed me?
Desperately.
But... London seems
to have tired me out.
Come.
Mr Carson,
is it true Mr Barrow's leaving?
Yes, and...
for what it's worth,
I think he was genuinely mistaken
over the, er... incident,
and he's sorry now,
which, of course, is no excuse.
I want to be sure
you'll give him a bad reference.
I'm sorry?
I can't let a man like that go
to work in innocent people's houses.
I will write him the character
I think he deserves.
Can I read it?
Certainly not!
Because I've been thinking...
I ought to report him to the police.
What?
It's my duty.
I know today thinking is much
more liberal. Now, just a minute.
I've never been called a liberal
in my life and I don't intend
to start now.
But I do not believe in scandal.
Mr Barrow will go, and when he does
I would like him to go quietly,
for the sake of the house,
the family,
and, for that matter, you.
I'm sorry, Mr Carson,
but I can't stay quiet if my
conscience prompts me differently.
I won't turn a blind eye to sin.
I've asked Ethel
to bring us some coffee.
Oh, I'm not supposed to drink coffee.
My mother doesn't approve.
Would you like something else?
Absolutely not.
After all, she won't find out
unless you tell her.
How is Lady Flintshire?
Incredibly busy.
Daddy works harder than a slave,
so she has to manage
everything else by herself.
I doubt he works
harder than a slave.
Cousin Isobel is very literal.
Now I have something for you.
Shall I pour, ma'am?
No, thank you. I'll do it.
These.
The first answers
to the advertisement.
Cousin Violet is trying
to find a new job for my cook.
That sounds rather inconvenient.
Cousin Violet has never let a matter
of convenience stand in the way
of a principle.
As the kettle said to the pot.
I'm to leave with no reference?
After working here for ten years?
I'm afraid my hands are tied.
I'll never get a job now, Mr Carson.
Does his lordship know about this?
No.
Then I'm going to tell him.
And how would you do that
without telling him the rest of it?
This wasn't Jimmy's idea.
Somebody's put him up to it.
He wouldn't be so unkind,
not left to himself.
I'm almost touched that you will
defend him under such circumstances,
but... there it is.
Well, can I stay here
for a day or two while I...
come up with some sort of plan?
Yes, I think I can allow that.
But that's the best I can do.
Thank you, Mr Carson.
At least it doesn't smell damp.
I think it's nice.
Or it will be
when it's got a lick of paint.
I can do that.
I can.
You're not climbing any ladders.
But yes,
together I think we can make it
really comfy.
What do they call extreme optimism?
They call it
making the best of things.
And that is what we will do.
You being in this room
is enough to make it nice.
Come here.
We should think of some things to do
while you're here.
Edith, you should take Rose
to Whitby market on Wednesday.
She'd enjoy that.
I can't.
I'm going to London on Wednesday.
Oh! Well, could I come?
Oh, but you've only just got here.
I thought you hated London.
Who told you that? Susan!
Oh, darling Mummy.
Well, should I correct her?
Oh, no. She's right, really, but...
I'm planning a surprise for her
and I need to go to London
to arrange it.
You won't give me away, will you?
Won't you stay with your parents?
I can't. It would spoil everything.
You can stay with me.
Aunt Rosamund won't mind,
and there's plenty of room.
I don't even know where you're
going. To see my editor,
to discuss my article.
I think I might
come up with you to London.
I'll ring the office in the morning.
I can stay at my club.
Don't do that. Aunt Rosamund
would love to have you.
And... I suspect I'll need help
controlling Rose.
Why do you say that? I'm not sure.
Instinct.
When your mother finds out, will
she mind? No, she'll be delighted.
And so grateful to all of you
for helping with my secret.
Besides, with Edith as my chaperone,
what harm can I come to?
But how can I help?
If our plan works, we'll be farming
a third of the estate directly.
And you can manage that?
We think so.
But we need you to think so too,
because Lord Grantham
definitely won't.
Are you drawing up
the battle lines? Poor Robert.
The post-war world
has not been kind to him.
How are you getting on
with the agent's house?
I hope Jarvis didn't leave it
a wreck. No, not at all.
But the furniture was his,
so I'll have to begin
in a state of Trappist simplicity.
I'm sure there's some stuff in
the attics here. We'll have a look.
What about Sybbie?
Won't it be lonely for her,
just you and Nanny
and nobody else for company?
I think it's right for both of us.
Mr Barrow?
What in heaven's name
are you doing out here?
I know you're leaving, but things
can't be as black as all that.
You're trained now. You can apply
for a position as a butler.
You don't know everything, then?
Then will you tell me everything?
I'm afraid if I dare do,
Mrs Hughes, that...
it will shock and disgust you.
Shock and disgust? My, my.
I think I have to hear it now.
Come on.
Lady Grantham -
the dowager, that is...
has been concerned that your history
here has left you lonely.
She's kind to concern herself.
It's not just that.
She believes you've made this house
a local topic of unwelcome
conversation.
Ah.
So she's placed
an advertisement for you
and she's got some replies.
The point is, you would go to your
new position with references from me
and from Mrs Hughes
and you would not have to refer
to your earlier life.
In effect, you'd be washed clean.
Yes?
Is the new maid working out?
No, not really.
I don't think she'll stay.
I miss Anna.
What do you call her
now she's your maid?
Anna, I'm afraid.
I can't very well call her Bates.
No.
What's this about?
Well...
You know Matthew wants
to come with you to London.
Why shouldn't he?
I just need to check which train
you're planning to come back on.
The three o'clock on Thursday. Why?
Can you promise not to let him
catch an earlier one?
Of course not.
What reason would I give?
You can think of something.
Please.
Oh, all right.
But why is everything
always so complicated?
We'll talk about it when
Matthew's back from London.
Can't I have a clue?
He should tell you. It's his idea.
God, it sounds ominous. What does?
Matthew has some ghastly scheme for
the estate and Tom's too frightened
to say what it is.
I need a drink.
You cannot allow him
to blackmail you like this.
And before you ask,
Thomas has told me the whole story.
I'm only sorry you had to listen
to such horrors.
Why? Do you think Thomas
is the first man of... that sort
that I've ever come across?
Well, I would hope so.
Well, he isn't.
And I'll tell you something else.
I think James may have led him on.
What?!
I cannot listen to such allegations.
Calm down.
I don't mean deliberately,
but he's a vain and silly flirt.
He may have given Thomas the wrong
impression without meaning to.
I can hardly believe
we're having this conversation.
Maybe not, but I won't sit by
and let that young whippersnapper
ruin a man for the rest of his life.
Not a man who was wounded
in the service of king and country.
We may have no choice.
These practices, with which
you're apparently so familiar,
are against the law.
I know that.
Very well, then.
If we stand up to James
and he goes to the police,
it will only put Thomas in prison,
which he will not thank you for.
Inspecting the love nest?
Just fetching some coal.
I envy you.
Whatever you say.
No, I mean it.
The happy couple,
and everyone's so pleased for you.
Can't imagine what that's like.
Perhaps you should try being nicer.
It's being nice
that got me into trouble.
What do you mean?
Never mind.
I'll be gone soon.
And now you're here...
you'll be glad of that.
Yes, I will be.
I assume I can count on you,
Mr Molesley.
Oh, I'll say. There's not much
I don't know about cricket.
You make me quite nervous.
So with you, me, James, Alfred,
both you hall boys,
that makes six from down here.
I can't play, Mr Carson,
but I can keep score.
Good. Very good.
So, with his lordship, Mr Crawley
and MR Branson, we're already ten.
What about you, Mr Barrow?
I think I'll be gone by then.
Yes, you will.
Where's Mary? I was looking for her
but Anna said she'd gone out.
She's away for the night.
She'll be back tomorrow. Oh?
Cora, is everything
as it should be between them?
Between Mary and Matthew?
Oh.
Yes, I think so. Why do you ask?
Well, I find I'm rather impatient
to get the succession settled.
Robert, it's still early days.
Luncheon is served, my lady.
Is it just us? Yes.
Tom's on the far side of the estate,
so he said he'd eat in the pub.
He's hiding from me.
Until Matthew's told me the worst.
Probably.
May I take the opportunity
to bring your lordship up to date
with the team? Are we in good shape?
I reckon that with three family
players and seven from downstairs,
we're only one short.
Two short. Branson won't play.
Mr Branson is busy at the moment.
Is he, my lady?
Might I point out
that we're all busy,
but we still find time
to support the honour of the house.
Yes. But that is not
the right road to travel, Carson,
if we want to remain
in her ladyship's good graces.
I know you all have
lots of things to do,
so just run about and do them.
I'll go and change.
But I thought we'd all have dinner
together and have a proper catch-up.
If you'd like, but please don't
let me be a nuisance. We could...
I insist. A good family gossip
will be my payment in kind.
Then of course we'd be delighted.
Good. We dine at half past eight.
Hello, operator?
Knightsbridge 4056.
I've been through those replies
to her ladyship's advertisement.
I don't think there's one
where I should be happier than here.
That's very flattering.
There was a nice letter
from a Mrs Watson...
but it was near Cheadle.
Cheadle's very close to where
Mr and Mrs Bryant live. Oh, I see.
And you feel that would
defeat the purpose
if the goal is
to leave your past behind you.
Don't you, ma'am?
Yes, I'm afraid I do.
It's a pity if it was the only one
that was appealing.
So it looks as if
I'll be staying on.
I'm sorry if it makes trouble
between you and the dowager.
Oh, don't worry about that.
If you'd gone, she'd have found some
other bone for us to fight over.
You look very pretty today.
I'm not sure how professional it is
of me to point that out.
Well, it's jolly nice of you.
So, er... business!
Now, I've read your piece.
The plight of ex-soldiers is not an
obvious topic for a woman's column.
I know it isn't very feminine,
but I felt so strongly about it,
I thought it was worth a try.
No, no, you misunderstand me.
I like the idea of a woman taking
a position on a man's subject.
Don't be afraid of being serious
when it feels right.
Really? Really.
No, I think
we're on to something new here.
The mature female voice in debate.
I don't like the sound of "mature".
No. Erm...
Balanced?
Yes. Let's go with "balanced".
Are you in town tonight and by any
chance looking for something to do?
I am, but sadly I'm spoken for.
That's a pity.
But you will let me know
when you're up in London again?
Why are you bothering with Thomas?
He's going. Good riddance.
I don't know.
Something he said.
I feel funny taking his job.
You haven't taken his job.
He filled in for you
while you were away, that's all.
Mm.
I might ask Mrs Hughes.
She usually knows what's going on.
Oh!
Which is more than YOU do.
Taxi!
Warwick Square, please.
Now I understand.
You're not too shocked, then?
No.
But why is Mr Carson?
It's not as if none of us knew.
I think the point is
we didn't know officially.
That's what Mr Carson finds hard.
He can't avoid the subject
any longer
because it's lying there on the mat.
And he can't stand up to Jimmy?
He says he's powerless.
And it's true we won't help Thomas
by putting him in prison.
I wouldn't wish that on any man.
Imagine me
feeling sorry for Thomas.
Life is full of surprises.
You don't think
we should have waited?
No! Why should your delicious dinner
be spoiled just because Rose
forgot the time?
It's my fault. I shouldn't have
let her out of my sight.
Nonsense. You had stuff to see to.
Talking of which,
how did you get on with your editor?
Oh. Quite well, I think.
How about you, Matthew?
I was only running errands.
My main thing is tomorrow.
Mead, what is it?
Come on.
This is the driver who took up Lady
Rose from outside the house, milady.
I came back because... she left
her scarf in the back of my cab.
How very good of you.
Go on. Tell them why they sent you
up to the dining room.
I know where she is, ma'am.
Your maid downstairs said
you might like to hear.
And she was right.
Where did she go?
First to Warwick Square,
to pick up her... friend.
And then you took her on somewhere?
Eventually. I was sat outside
for the best part of two hours.
How very expensive.
When they came out, they said
they wanted to go to a club.
The Blue Dragon, on Greek Street.
And what sort of club is that?
Well... You know.
That's the point. I don't.
This is like the outer circle from
Dante's Inferno. The OUTER circle?
There she is.
Heavens, what a transformation!
And that, presumably,
is the friend she spent
two hours with in Warwick Square.
Let's not start down that track.
Oh, my...!
How on earth did you find me?
How do you do?
I'm a cousin of Rose's mother.
Lady Rosamund Painswick.
And this is Terence Margadale.
How do you do? Please, sit down.
Can you bring some more glasses?
Tell me, where is MRS Margadale?
She's in the country, at the...
Erm...
Er, Terence used to work for Daddy,
so he's more of
a family friend, really.
Oh! So Cousin Shrimpie
will be pleased to hear about him?
No, please...
Why don't we dance?
Now look, I think I can get Rosamund
and Edith to keep their mouths shut
if you come with us now and have
nothing more to do with this man,
at least not until
you're out of our charge.
But he's... he's terribly unhappy,
and it's not his fault.
His wife is absolutely horrid.
Married men who wish to seduce young
women always have horrid wives.
I suggest you meet Mrs Margadale
before you come to any
final conclusions.
You're wrong. He's in love with me.
He wants to marry me as soon as
he can get a divorce.
And when will that be?
Well... it's terribly difficult.
Yes, I thought it might be.
Now, will you accept my conditions
or do I throw you to Lady Rosamund?
Why are you helping me?
I'm on the side of the downtrodden.
Excuse me.
I rather like Warwick Square.
A sort of Belgravia
without the bustle.
We haven't been there very long.
Rose is feeling rather tired
so we're leaving.
Won't you at least stay for a...?
Well, no.
No, I'm glad she's staying.
But one forgets about parenthood.
The on-and-on-ness of it.
Were you a very involved mother
with Robert and Rosamund?
Does it surprise you? A bit.
I'd imagined them surrounded
by nannies and governesses,
being starched and ironed
to spend an hour with you after tea.
Yes, but it was an hour every day.
I see, yes.
How tiring.
After the money turned up
from Mr Swire,
things went back to normal.
Mr Carson, may I have a word?
I'll leave you. Just...
Well?
When's Mr Barrow leaving?
I'm not sure.
He's lost his job. Why can't he
just go? I find it very awkward.
He made a mistake.
You're still in one piece.
Why do you have to be
such a big girl's blouse about it?
I'm sorry, Mr Carson,
but I won't change my mind.
I suppose you know
who's put him up to this, Mr Carson.
That Mr Bates is gobby, isn't he?
Why do you say that?
Everyone talked about him
as if he could walk on water,
but he's got a mouth on him.
What did he say?
He was sticking up for Mr Barrow.
Is this because of Mr Carson
not giving him a reference?
I don't think it's right. Do you?
Yes, I bloody well do
think it's right!
You know nothing about it.
What's happened?
What did I say?
I shouldn't get involved, dear.
If you'll take my advice,
I should stay out of it.
Has there been
any progress with Ethel?
No. I'm sorry to disappoint you
but she doesn't want to go.
Not one of them was right?
One. A Mrs Watson.
But the house was near
where the Bryants live.
And to be honest,
I suspect that was the reason.
A chance to see little Charlie
from time to time.
Well, I can't blame her for that.
Of course not.
But the Bryants
would be bound to find out,
which would only lead
to more heartbreak.
I'll write to you as soon as I hear,
but it's extremely unlikely
there is anything wrong at all.
This may prove
an expensive journey for you.
May I ask you a question, Dr Ryder?
Has my wife been to see you?
I'm not aware of treating
a Mrs Crawley.
But even if I had, I could not
possibly comment on it. Of course.
It's only... I can't bear
to think of her being worried
when I know very well that
if anyone's to blame, it's me.
I'm not sure blame is
a very useful concept in this area.
Please believe me
that probability and logic
indicate a Crawley baby
yowling in its crib before too long.
Thank you.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Mrs Levenson for Dr Ryder.
This should buck you up.
Why did you go without saying,
when I knew all along it was me?
You know nothing of the sort.
In fact, it was me.
What do you mean?
There WAS something wrong,
with...
Actually, I can't talk about
this sort of thing, even to you.
You sound like Robert.
Well, I am his daughter.
The fact is...
it meant a small operation.
What?
It's all right. It was weeks ago.
That's why I've been keeping you
at arm's length.
I thought you'd gone off me.
Anyway, today was just to see
if all is well, and he says it is.
He says I'm to get in touch with him
in six months' time
but that I'll be pregnant
before then.
So... now we can start making babies.
I feel very guilty
not telling Susan about last night.
Mummy wouldn't understand.
Nor do I.
What were you thinking,
a respectable, well-born young woman
going out with a married man?
Rose knows it all depends on her
behaviour for the rest of her stay.
One false step
and I shall personally
telephone Lady Flintshire.
Very well.
But I don't approve.
Rose, you've obviously
read too many novels about young
women admired for their feistiness.
Do you think they will keep quiet?
I expect so, as long as you
stick to your side of the bargain.
Even Cousin Rosamund? She didn't like
being made to keep the secret.
Probably because she knows
that Granny will be furious.
You see? How I turn it,
first this way,
and now that.
Alfred, what's the matter?
I'm not easy
about this business with Mr Barrow.
Well, why not take a turn
with Mr Moseley's bat?
That'll put a smile on your face.
Is Mr Carson really
not giving Mr Barrow a reference?
What will he do
if he hasn't got a reference?
He could always go abroad. He might
do well in America, Mr Barrow.
Seems a bit drastic. Why should he
go abroad? Keep your nose out of it.
Why won't someone
tell us what's going on?
Because you wouldn't understand it.
I very much hope.
Why didn't Carson tell me?
He's the one who's being undermined.
It's a very difficult subject
for him to discuss. I can imagine.
But it's not as if
we didn't all know about Barrow.
That's what I said to Mrs Hughes.
If I shouted blue murder every time
someone tried to kiss me at Eton,
I'd have gone hoarse in a month.
What a tiresome fellow.
It's not the boy's fault, my lord.
He's been whipped up,
told if he doesn't see it through,
we'd all suspect him
of batting for the same team.
Crikey! But who'd do that?
Who's got it in for Barrow?
Miss O'Brien.
O'Brien? I thought
they were as thick as thieves.
Not now, my lord.
Now, I've spoken to your mother.
She has a new plan
for when you leave here.
But aren't I going back to London?
Oh, no. It's so horrid and dusty.
What is Mummy's plan?
They're opening Duneagle early.
You're to go there.
On my own? No. Your Aunt Agatha
will keep you company.
Alone in Scotland with Aunt Agatha?
She can't be serious.
I know. Lady Agatha isn't
much of a party person, I admit.
This is all because I went up
to London to see Terence, isn't it?
How did she find out?
Who gave me away?
I don't know who Terence is.
Of course. It's not your fault,
Aunt Violet. But they promised...
Don't shoot the messenger. I'm only
relaying your mother's orders.
You're to stay for the cricket match
and head north the next day.
Perhaps I'll run away.
Not this time.
My maid will travel with you
so you have someone to talk to
on the journey.
I won't be held a prisoner forever.
No. One day you'll be older
and out of our power.
But not yet.
Prison's changed you.
There was a time when
nothing was too bad for me
as far as you were concerned.
Prison HAS changed me.
You do know Miss O'Brien
is behind it?
I knew someone was.
Jimmy'd never think of it
for himself.
Doesn't it bother you
that she'll get away with it?
Not really.
Without a reference,
after ten years here,
you'll never work again.
Not in England.
But elsewhere maybe.
A cousin in Bombay. I might go there.
I like the sun.
You must know something about Miss
O'Brien you can use against her.
You've heard of the phrase
"to know when you're beaten"?
Well, I'm beaten, Mr Bates.
I'm well and truly beaten.
Then give me the weapon
and I'll do the work.
What can I say
that will make her change her mind?
It is not how we do things!
Many of the farmers' families have
been at Downton as long as we have.
We need to see
more profits from the farm!
Here we go. Profit, profit, profit!
We cannot go forward with no income.
But why not tackle it gradually?
Perhaps buy some time
by investing your capital.
I hear of schemes daily that'll
double whatever's put into them,
or treble it, or more.
Many offer high rewards.
Very few deliver them.
There's a chap in America, er...
Charles Ponzi,
who offers a huge return
after 90 days.
Harry Stoke has gone in
with a bundle...
Then Harry Stoke, whoever he is,
is a fool. But if I could find out...
Last time you took an interest in
investment, you ruined the family!
Now look here!
As captain of this ship,
Robert's entitled to some respect.
He didn't mean any disrespect. He
does a marvellous impression of it.
We're giving the farmers a choice,
that's all.
If they sell,
the larger units will let us meet
the challenges of the modern world.
We need to build something
that will last, not stand by
and watch it crumble into dust.
What about the tenants?!
What about the men and women
who put their trust in us?
Is this fair to them?
I don't believe so.
But isn't the most important thing
for them, or us,
to maintain Downton
as a source of employment?
So you're against me too?
It seems to me your plan adds up to
carrying on as if nothing's changed,
to spend Matthew's money
keeping up the illusion,
then, when we've fallen into
a bottomless pit of debt,
we'll sell up and go.
So yes, I believe Matthew is right.
I see.
You seem to be agreed that
there's no place for me in all this.
So obviously it's time for me
to take a back seat.
Hello. Is that the Daily Telegraph
information desk?
I want to find out
about a London editor.
Michael Gregson, of the Sketch.
Just some general stuff.
His education,
what he's done since then.
And... a little
about his private life.
But why here?
I don't like the idea
of her being our first visitor.
I want to be away from the others.
I don't know why you're doing this.
You don't even like Thomas.
Because I know what it is
to feel powerless.
To see a life slide away and there's
nothing you can do to stop it.
Quite the orator.
Have you thought about
standing for Parliament?
Oh, yes. Very nice.
It'll be even better
with a bit of money spent on it.
Can I get you some tea?
If I'm staying long enough.
I don't know what it is
Mr Bates wants to see me about.
You'll have time for tea.
Will that be all, ma'am?
There is one thing.
There was a letter delivered by hand
this afternoon.
It's from the dowager. She wants us
to call on her in the morning.
But why would she want ME? No doubt
we'll find out in the morning.
Well, I am surprised to find
that you're a fan Mr Oscar Wilde.
You've known about Mr Barrow
all along, so what's changed now?
Perhaps I've come to my senses.
You mean you've found a way
to be even nastier than usual.
Get back in the knife box,
Miss Sharp.
I want you to persuade Jimmy
to let Mr Barrow have a reference
so when he leaves here
he can start again.
Why would Jimmy listen to me?
I won't do it.
I think you will.
I'm going.
Sort it out by this evening.
Or? Or you'll find your secret
is no longer safe with me.
I'm just saying
I think you've made your point.
To let it go now would be
the gentlemanly thing to do.
You said that if I let it go
they'd think I was
up to the same thing,
that I wasn't a proper man.
If you'd done nothing, yes.
But this way you'll come across as
merciful and not vindictive.
Do you see?
I never wanted to push it this far.
Then you'll be glad to stop it.
You're sure I won't
be made to look a fool?
Far from it.
I think they'll hold you higher
in their estimation.
Ah, James. Upstairs, please.
May I have a word with you, please,
Mr Carson, before we go up?
But why London?
You've only just got back.
I've had some bad news, that's all.
What sort of bad news?
Never mind. It's not our business.
How's the cricket team coming along?
We're still two short.
And you're still determined
not to play?
It's not that I WON'T play.
I CAN'T play. I don't know how.
Stop twisting his arm.
Any news on the move, Tom? We're
going to miss you both so much.
You told Matthew
not to twist his arm.
Now you're doing exactly the same.
I just think children are happier
in families. I'm sorry but I do.
Well, I'm glad that's settled.
But I suppose Barrow
will have to go.
My lord?
He's so good at cricket.
I know we were soundly beaten last
year, but he got most of our runs.
I thought we just wanted him to have
a reference so he could find work
when he leaves.
I know, but now that I think
about it, Carson ought to
insist that he stays on.
He needs to re-establish
his authority over James.
Couldn't Mr Barrow just stay
till after the match and then go?
That seems rather unkind.
Wouldn't we be using him?
He might not want to stay, my lord,
after the unpleasantness.
I think he will.
But don't forget the cricket.
I won't, my lord.
See how my grip is firm,
but tender.
Cherish the ball. Don't crush it.
Right. Gabriel, have a try.
Is it true you've given in
and let Mr Barrow get away with it?
It was dragging on and on. At least
this way we'll be rid of him.
I heard his lordship wants him
to stay for the cricket match.
It won't be for much longer.
Then he'll get his reference and go.
And good riddance.
I'm... going over to Windmill Farm,
to see what we can do
with the outbuildings.
Would you like to come with me?
I'm sure you can manage on your own.
Aren't you going?
I'll meet him there later.
He's putting a good face on it,
but you know he wants you with him
on this, more than anything.
I should not serve him well.
I don't have the instincts
for what he wants to do.
You mean you're not a tradesman?
Your word, not mine.
Shall I tell you how I look at it?
Every man or woman
who marries into this house,
every child born into it,
has to put their gifts
at the family's disposal.
I'm a hard worker,
and I've some knowledge of the land.
Matthew knows the law and the nature
of business. Which I do not.
You understand the responsibilities
we owe to the people round here,
those who work for the estate
and those that don't.
It seems to me if we could manage
to pool all of that,
if we each do what we can do,
then Downton has a real chance.
You're very eloquent.
You're a good spokesman
for Matthew's vision.
Better than he has been recently.
So you'll give us your backing?
I'll think about it.
On one condition.
You play cricket for the house.
We all have to do what we can do.
For God's sake,
if it means that much to you.
Oh!
You didn't expect to find ME here.
No.
I thought the only person
who could tell us with any accuracy
the Bryants' response
to Ethel's working nearby
were the Bryants themselves.
Lady Grantham wrote to me
explaining your wish.
Well... it was only that Mrs Watson
had answered the advertisement...
I know the circumstances.
Just as I know that you would like
to see how Charlie's getting on.
As it happens,
I've been uncomfortable
about keeping a mother from her son.
Although I would not want to confuse
him until he's much older, if then...
You wouldn't have to confuse him.
I've already worked it out.
I'm his old nanny, employed by you
when he was first born.
But what about when he talks about
you to Mr Bryant? You will please
leave Mr Bryant to me.
Now, Ethel, you must write to
Mrs Watson today and get it settled.
And I'll be able to see Charlie!
It won't be easy.
It'll be easier than not seeing him.
Very much easier.
And if Mr Barrow is to stay on,
what would he be? My valet?
You can make him under-butler. Then
your dinners will be grand enough
for Chu Chin Chow.
And he can apply to be a butler
when he does leave.
But that would make him my superior.
Oh, I don't know. Under-butler,
head valet. There's not much in it.
The question remains,
how do we convince James?
Well...
It's his lordship
who wants Mr Barrow to stay on,
so I think his lordship
can bring it about.
Is this worth it?
I've no time to learn anything.
Couldn't I just trust
to beginner's luck? Certainly not.
I want you to profit
from my skills in gratitude
for bringing Robert round.
Not completely. Not yet.
Elbow up.
You won't make a gentleman of me,
you know.
You can teach me to fish, ride
and shoot, but I'd still be
an Irish Mick in my heart.
So I should hope.
There! See?
You're getting the hang of it.
I'm sorry if this is inconvenient.
It's unexpected, not inconvenient.
I suppose I'd better just say it.
Please do.
I had the impression on my last visit
that you were flirting.
Giving signs
that you found me attractive.
If I'm wrong, then I apologise.
You're not wrong.
But since then I have discovered
that you are, in fact, married.
Yes.
I'm afraid I find the idea
of a married man flirting
with me wholly repugnant.
So I must hand in
my resignation at once.
No. It's true, I am married, but
I hope you'll allow me to explain.
Explain what? I am familiar
with the institution of marriage.
Yes, but not with this one.
My wife is in an asylum,
and she has been for some years.
Lizzie was a wonderful person.
I loved her very much.
It took me a long time to accept
that the woman I knew was gone...
and wouldn't be coming back.
Then why haven't you got a divorce?
I can't. A... lunatic
is not deemed responsible.
She's neither the guilty
nor the innocent party.
It means that I'm... tied
for the rest of my life to a...
a madwoman,
who doesn't even know me.
I can't begin to tell you how much
it cheers me to read your column
and to meet when we do.
I hope very much
you'll consider staying on.
Heads.
Ah. Well, there we are.
Yes!
I'm glad everything's settled
with Ethel,
but I trust you can find another
cook without too much difficulty.
Preferably one
with a blameless record
so my house ceases to be
a topic of gossip, which is
really what this is all about.
Well, if Ethel wants to be part of
her son's life, even a little part,
who are we to stand in her way?
If you'd had to sell Charlie
to the butcher to be chopped up
as stew to achieve the same ends,
you would have done so.
Well, happily it was not needed.
Howzat!
Well shot, sir!
Well played, Barrow. Thank you.
Excellent innings.
I thought I was helping him
get out of our lives for good.
Now he ranks higher than I do.
I've been a damned fool.
By the way, what was that phrase
he gave you to say to Miss O'Brien?
You can tell me now, surely.
If you keep it under your hat.
It was "her ladyship's soap".
What?
I can't make any sense of it either,
but that's what he said.
"Her ladyship's soap."
And it worked.
It's down to you, Molesley,
last man in.
We're in good shape thanks to Barrow,
but we could do with a bonus.
Don't worry, I'll show them
a thing or two. That's the spirit.
Well done, Papa. I did my best.
We'll just have to hope it's enough.
Anna says we are to expect
great things of Molesley. Ah.
Out!
Well bowled.
As usual, our expectations
are disappointed.
Let's have some tea!
Who gave me away?
Was it you? Certainly not!
In case you don't know,
I'm being sent north tomorrow
with a monster for a jailer!
Well, what did she expect,
carrying on with a married man
as if her home were in a tree?
Granny, who told you?
How could you have done that,
after you promised?
But Mama said YOU told her.
I just filled in the details.
I never said a word!
Have you tricked me, Mama?
Tricked? I'm not a conjurer.
I only did what was necessary to
preserve the honour of the family.
In other words, you tricked me.
James!
You put up a very good show out
there. Well done. Thank you, m'lord.
As a matter of fact,
I wanted to thank you
for your generosity with Barrow.
Letting him stay on
shows a real largeness of spirit.
Stay on?
Mr Barrow's staying on?
As under-butler.
I was given the impression
you'd allowed it.
I allowed him to have
a decent reference when he left.
But you won't mind too much,
will you?
Oh, by the way, congratulations
on your appointment as first footman.
What?
Thank you, m'lord. Very much.
Lord Grantham, I believe.
The same.
Looking for a Mr Alfred Nugent,
my lord.
And you are...? Inspector Stanford
and Sergeant Brand, York Police.
Alfred can't have got into trouble
with the police. That's not possible.
He's made a complaint
concerning a Mr Thomas Barrow,
making an assault of a... criminal
nature on another of your employees.
That is a very serious allegation.
Serious enough to bring us here
to interrupt your cricket match.
If you'd point out
the young gentleman.
He's over... I'll fetch him.
We'll go with you. I think it's
better to leave it to his lordship.
I'm sure he can get
to the bottom of it.
But I know what I saw,
and it weren't right.
I'm not asking you to abandon
your beliefs, Alfred,
just to introduce a little kindness
into the equation.
Am I not to stand up against evil?
Evil?
Thomas does not choose
to be the way he is.
And what harm was done, really, that
his life should be destroyed for it?
Well... Let he who is without sin
cast the first stone.
Are you without sin, Alfred?
For I am certainly not.
Sorry about your son, Mr Molesley.
Don't be.
He talks such a lovely game. He could
always talk a good game of cricket.
He just couldn't play it.
Just as I thought.
There's been a mix-up.
Alfred here witnessed
some rough-housing between two
of the staff and misinterpreted it.
Why did you make the telephone call
without checking your facts?
I'm very much afraid to say he was
a bit squiffy. Weren't you, Alfred?
I made the call
before I knew what I were doing.
I'd been at the cider.
You'd what?!
Oh, I think we can
overlook it this once.
Don't you, Carson?
So there's nothing to investigate.
I'm terribly sorry to have wasted
your time.
Would you care to have some tea?
No, thank you, Lord Grantham.
I think we've got the measure of it.
Good luck with your match.
Where is Nanny?
Gone to get some baby paraphernalia.
Shall I tell her
you're looking for her?
No.
No, I'll be here anyway.
You're very good to play.
I don't know why
I made such a fuss about it.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
If I were to say I'd live with you
while Sybbie's little,
and that we wouldn't move out
until she's older,
would you mind?
I should be delighted.
And I know
it's what Sybil would want.
I think you're right.
Tom says Robert's ready
to get behind the plan.
I'm glad.
So we'll be building a new kingdom
while we make our little prince.
I'm looking forward to both
enormously.
Right, gentlemen! Time's up!
We're about to start again.
I hope I can count on you
not to laugh when I drop the ball.
You can always count on me.
I know that.
I didn't think it was possible
to love as much as I love you.
Matthew, hurry up!
You're keeping everyone waiting!
I've got to go.
Of course you have.
Tom seems to think
you might be coming round.
Well, he's brought me round,
more like, but yes.
All right.
Let's give it a go
and see what the future brings.
Thank you.
Catch it!
Great stuff.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.